

# ASMA SAEED AL FAHMI CEO - RESEARCH SCIENTIST – MEDICAL CONSULTANT

Contact information

Dh.asma@hotmail.com

**()** +966 541511183

**y** 

twitter.com/drasma.z

https://www.linkedin.com/in/asma-saeed-mph-mshi-36928394

#### **LANGUAGES**

ARABIC: MOTHER TONGUE

ENGLISH: FLUENT IN READING, WRITING AND

SPEAKING.

#### **SKILLS**

communication
development and creativity
Teamwork
Project management
Leadership and management
Planning and Organizing
Training and Consulting

Founding and development

Team Leadership

## ACCREDITATION AND LICENSE

Certified Healthcare Quality Professionals Course CPHQ.

project management Professional course ( PMP)
Certified Digital Business Leader (CDBL)Certified Digital
Transformation Professional (CDTP)

Executive Leadership and Management Course PMI Risk Management Professional (PMI-RMP) Course Training of Trainers (TOT)

## **ACHIEVEMENT**

- Development of a Saudi e-Health Literacy scale for non-communicable diseases in Saudi Arabia: Using Integrated Health Literacy Dimensions, International Journal for Quality in Health Care.
- The association between the social media use and the level of oral health knowledge among female students in secondary schools in Riyadh.
- Building up "Smoking Cessation" application in the Apple store.

#### **RECOMMENDATIONS**

Prof. Salah AlMandil , director of the Health informatics .**WHO** Geneva .Switzerland.
Prof. Shaker Hosam . Head of Electronic Public Health association.

Byron Lawrence Crape, MSPH, PhD Director of the MPH Program Nazarabyev University School of Medicine.

Prof. Fred Hagigi, PhD, DrPH, MBA, MPH, MAEd from UCLA .USA.

# **PROFILE**

Medical Specialist, MPH, MsHI with +15 Years of Experience Including Medical Consulting, Public Relations and Negotiations, Collaborations and Agreements, Digital Transformations, Quality Management, Strategic Planning and Management, With Proven Track Record in Leadership, Teamwork, People Management, Analytical Problem Solving, And Achieving Result & Target

#### **EDUCATION**

Master's Degree in Public Health – Health Informatics with Honors.

College of Medicine

KING SAUD UNIVERSITY

BSc in Oral Health

College of Medical Applied Medicine

KINF SAUD UNIVERSITY

# **EXPERIENCE**

Research Scientist (Research Medical Center in Prince Sultan Military Medical City) 2021-now

Medical Consultant In The Saudi Health Council (Part Time)

2022-Now

CEO CHIEF executive office of the SAUDI DENTAL HYGIENE SOCIETY (SDHS)

CEO AND FOUNDER Of the Charity Dental Treatment Initiative (CDTI).

2019 -now

2020

2020 -Now

Board of Directors in Saudi Dental Hygienist Society (SDHS).

2018 -now

Board of Directors in (Mashorati) for preventing medical error and supporting health practicians

2020 – now

Partner in 3 different dental privet clinics: responsible for **managing overall operations** (strategic plan , financial management and marketing )

2019 -now

Head of Public Relation in the SDHS (Marketing. sponsor, negotiations, agreements).

2018 -now

Member of the DENTAL RESEARCH GROUP.

2020 - 2022

Active member in Health informatics research chair in KSU.

2014 -2018.

Continuous Quality and Improvement CQI and Patient safety
Representative. 2017 -2020

Health Informatics Representative with CERNER and R4. 2016 -2020